## **Tomas Makaj**

Mahopac, New York | 914-483-6097 | tmakajcoding@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Medium |

## **Software Engineer**

Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and ReactJs based programming and a background in Construction Project Management. Possess strong skills in problem solving, time management and is extremely detail-oriented. Takes pleasure in addressing day-to-day problems as challenges to better my own skills.

## **Technologies and Languages**

JavaScript, React, Ruby, Rails, Redux, SQL, PostgreSQL, Heroku, Postman, Sinatra, Git, CSS

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Not Shake Shack - Github

Food ordering app for restaurant brick and mortar locations.

- Utilized JWT Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Engineered functional backend database allowing it to be self-sustaining using Ruby on Rails.
- Created the frontend using ReactJs allowing the user to navigate the website and update data as needed
- Integrated a stripe checkout using the Stripe API

## Lucid Real Estate - Github

Housing app that allows a user to add homes to their portfolio

- Built a backend database using Ruby on Rails
- Enabled ReactJs front end to fetch and render all the information from the database
- Crafted a sign in modal to persist on the frontend with scroll
- Distributed different data from the database by using multiple useEffects

## My Portfolio - Github

Personal website to be used for personal career marketing and branding

- Created and separated all components that kept the DOM in sync with the data
- Integrated useState hook to track state in multiple function components
- Built a modern and responsive navbar that persisted with scrolling
- Utilized multiple contact options to help diversify my personal brand

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Taconic RemodelNew York, New YorkProject Manager06/2020 - 01/2022

- Supervised day-to-day activities by delegating authority
- Collaborated with specialized subcontractors to perform all or portions of the work
- Managed renovations on multi-million dollar projects

## Majestic Home Improvement

Assistant Project Manager

New York, New York 07/2019 - 02/2020

- Consulted with clients on progress and worked with management to resolve any issues
- Assigning and prioritizing activities and monitoring operating job standards

## **EDUCATION**

## Flatiron School Full Stack Web Development New York, New York 08/2022 - 11/2022

## **Fordham University**

Organizational Leadership/ Bachelor of Arts

New York, New York 08/2014- 05/2018